STHEMBISO BUTHELEZI

Contact number: 063 601 5960 | email: sthembisobuthelezi774@gmail.com Nationality: South African| Gender: Male | Location: Midrand, Johannesburg | Date of Birth: 12 /07/1996

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated intermediate Software Developer and Azure Cloud Service Administrator who is currently working at ejoobi

responsible for developing and maintaining back-end code using new tools and technical development to drive improvement throughout the entire software development lifecycle. Having 4 years of working as a software developer and has been recognised as a National Diploma graduate at the University Of Technology (TUT). Currently looking for a software developer opportunity that will allow me to work alongside an expert team of developers and will challenge my developer and problem-solving skills and allow me to continue to develop my knowledge and potential

EDUCATION

2016 - 2023 N DIP Information Technology (Software

Developer)

Tshwane University of Technology

2010 - 2015 Grade 12

Nsikayendlu High School

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nov 2022- To Date intermediate Software Developer | Company: ejoobi

- Researching, designing, developing ideas for new programs and managing software programs
- Work with experienced team members to review new and existing code and/or perform unit testing
- Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability
- Using the Azure Portal and command's Service to manage the applications and data running in Azure
- Taking lead on projects as needed
- Learn new programming languages or cloud computing, and better assist other team members.
- Integration with MVC
- Programming languages (SPRING BOOT(JAVA), ANGULAR JS, NODE JS)

14/01/2020 - 14/01/2022 Internship as a software developer | BonConnect

- Work with developers to design algorithms and flowcharts
- Collaborating with the front-end developers and other team members to establish objectives and design more functional, unite codes to enhance the user experience
- Independently install, customize and integrate commercial software packages.
- Programming languages (PHP, JAVA, SQL/MySQL, HTML5, CSS AND JAVASCRIPT

ACHIEVEMENTS

 National Diploma in Information Technology

SKILLS

Creative writing

- Ability to work under pressure
- Ability to work independently and Part of a team
- Ability to Priorities and complete work under
- Ability to meet Deadlines

Programming skills

Java, Spring Boot, Web Services. UI development, Angular. PDF, report generation, PL/SQL. Database development. C#, OpenJDK 8. Spring Boot 2, Web Service. REST Service, Git, SQL Server databases, Open API Specification Swagger, design, code, test, debug document applications, design, latest design patterns,

Languages

deployment.

English isiZulu